Ali RajabNezhad

Software Engineer

AliRn1997@gmail.com 📞 +989037853055 🎧 GitHub.com/AliRn76 in LinkedIn.com/in/AliRn76

SUMMARY

As a skilled software developer with 7 years of experience, I've built a Python web framework called Panther $\mathscr E$. My skills include writing code, managing projects, and working well with teams. Throughout my career, I've shown that I'm good at leading and helping people grow.

SKILLS

Programming Languages/ Web Frameworks: Python | Go | Django | FastAPI | ...

Databases: PostgreSQL | MongoDB | Redis

Monitoring: Grafana | Prometheus | Loki | FluentBit | Promtail

Other Tools & Technologies: Git | Linux | Docker | Docker Swarm | Kubernetes | Kind | NginX | Traefik | Ansible | AWS S3 | GitHub Actions | GitLab CI | Vagrant | Celery | RabbitMQ | Kafka | WebSocket | Metabase | Apache Airflow

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer present

Yektanet (Serving) &

- Boosted company revenue by 5% through optimization of the Auction algorithm.
- Delivered requested features, ensuring alignment with user needs.
- Optimized Redis Cluster performance by identifying and removing ~1M redundant keys.

05/2024 **Software Engineer**

Yektanet (Ghollak) 🔗

- Enhanced Core Architecture and Optimized existing codebase
- Refactored queries and improved database performance
- Engineered a new CRM service and migrated the old CRM database to it and moved ~2700 files to s3, overall with only 568 seconds of downtime
- Designed and implemented a push-notification system
- · Co-led team meetings, improving efficiency and speeding up decision-making processes.

Open Source Project

PantherPy.GitHub.io ∅

- Async Python Web Framework
- Weekly Download ~= 2,628 €
- Third Fastest Python Web Framework → Benchmark Ø

Software Engineer

12/2022 - 11/2023

11/2023 - 05/2024

Digikala (Digify.shop) ♂

- · Engineered robust database replication systems, enhancing data consistency across servers
- Implemented Traefik-based load balancer
- Refactored slow SQL queries, reducing average query execution time by 30%
- Integrated third-party shipping/payment services (Miare, Alopeyk, Digikala drop shipping, Zarinpal, ...)

01/2022 - 12/2022**Software Engineer**

Hamrahe Aval 🔗

- Engineered a Learning Management System (LMS) for Shad.ir
- Designed and implemented a local object storage system, similar to MinIO
- Developed and integrated "Bot Father" ⊘ for Rubika.ir ⊘, serving over 37 million users

Backend Team Lead 01/2020 – 12/2021

ReVision

At a startup company, I developed the backend of several products:

- Sandbad Super App AshinehStudio Podingo.com 🔗
- ReVPN ReMenu Quiztion Game

Freelance 2018 – 2020

• Implemented several applications (HiCoffee, SportHub, ...)

EDUCATION

PhD of Computer Engineering (System Architecture)

2024 – present

Islamic Azad University - Tehran North Branch

Master of Computer Engineering (Software)

2021 - 2023

Islamic Azad University - Tehran West Branch

Bachelor of Computer Engineering

2016 - 2021

Islamic Azad University - Tehran North Branch